<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: english | 网络寻租]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.linjunhalida.com/blog/categories/english/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.linjunhalida.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-19T01:11:26+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.linjunhalida.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[机械唯物主义]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[English Matters]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.linjunhalida.com/blog/english-matters/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-12T15:07:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.linjunhalida.com/blog/english-matters</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/fD9By.jpg" alt="image" /></p>

<p>This is the first time I'm blogging in English here,
And from now on, I will keep on doing it regularly.</p>

<h2>Why Blogging?</h2>

<p>I'm blogging for good reason. As a blogger, I'm not elegant or productive, or even continus,
I had drop blogging for quite a long time; Hopefully I struggle to bring all things togather again.
Blogging is not easy as it starts, it needs patience, persistence, continus self-improvement.
And it worth that, I told you reasons.</p>

<p>Blogging is a process to help you <strong>organize thoughts</strong>. Things are not as clear as you think it is, before you write it down.</p>

<p>Blogging is <strong>practice of writting</strong>, there is no need to emphisize the importance of writing.</p>

<p>Blogging is a <strong>good communication</strong>, small talks are good, but too small for serious disscussion, and hard to summon all things up.</p>

<p>Blogging is <strong>self advertizing</strong>. There is no better way to know a person's mind then seeing things written by him, and writting itself can reflat lots of great attributes.</p>

<h2>Why English Blogging?</h2>

<p>And there comes another question: Why I start english blogging? here are some reasons:</p>

<p>English is <strong>THE</strong> universal language, practice it, is a good investment.</p>

<p>The people using English is <strong>better</strong> than The people using Chinese (statistically).</p>

<p>The thinking process is very <strong>different</strong> between English and Chinese. It brings me an opportunity of switching.</p>

<h2>conclusion</h2>

<p>According to the reason I list above and the condition I'm currently in, English blogging is profitable.
Maybe it is also a good option for you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
