<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: english | 网络寻租]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.linjunhalida.com/blog/categories/english/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.linjunhalida.com/"/>
  <updated>2024-07-07T15:11:02+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.linjunhalida.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[机械唯物主义]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2014 Summary]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.linjunhalida.com/blog/english-2014-summary/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-04T12:00:19+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.linjunhalida.com/blog/english-2014-summary</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another year has passed, time goes so fast with so little change to myself.
Whether finished or not, new year resolution needs to be written.
It can make your future more clear, and let you understand more about what happens last year.</p>

<h2>Review</h2>

<p>First take a look at <a href="http://blog.linjunhalida.com/blog/2013-summary/">last year</a>, what I&rsquo;ve done or not done:</p>

<ul>
<li>Tech: Have some archivement, finish nothing in the plan.</li>
<li>Job: Major change, it take chances to get a good job.</li>
<li>English: Stalled, it is hard to continue learning without purpose.</li>
<li>Health: Got some muscle in the first half of the year, stalled later.</li>
<li>Mate: I&rsquo;m got lucky.</li>
<li>Piano: Leak of time and money, had to drop it for now.</li>
</ul>


<p>Not done well, issues:</p>

<ul>
<li>Didn&rsquo;t review the objectives. forget them.</li>
<li>Have objective, didn&rsquo;t implement them.</li>
<li>Have a plan, always delay it.</li>
</ul>


<p>I need take care of this issues for next year.</p>

<h2>What is happened at 2014</h2>

<h3>Big things</h3>

<ul>
<li>I was working at <a href="http://srslyy.com">Hospital of Shangrao IT department</a>, All the computer &amp; network related stuff. It does not fit for me totally, the only reason I take it is because I need a identity in Shangrao for get a decent date. It turns out that it&rsquo;s not working, so I quit it latterly.</li>
<li>I join to organize <a href="http://sqmqnh.org">三清媚青年汇</a>, take part in several big event, and lots of small ones. Because it has no strong purpose and outcome, This organization goes no further.</li>
<li>In the later half of the year, I found an remote coding job, <a href="https://ruby-china.org/topics/22879">it is need recruit now</a>.</li>
<li>I met my girlfriend, and this relationship is advancing very well.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Tech</h3>

<ul>
<li>I developed an notice system when I work at the hospital, it use node-webkit, can auto-update itself.</li>
<li>I create <a href="http://ffuu.org">a demo website</a> for learning rails.</li>
<li>Finish reading a <a href="http://book.douban.com/subject/24749842/">algorithm book</a>, know something about algorithm.</li>
<li>Finish reading <a href="http://book.douban.com/subject/4246128/">Understanding Cryptography</a>, got some basic knowlege about this domain.</li>
<li>Read lots of document about protocols, like ftp，pptp，l2tp，ssh，SSL.</li>
<li>Dig deeper on Rails, read Gem source code, start reading Rails source code.</li>
<li>Learn how to create single page complex static website, using middleman/haml/sass/spine/coffeescript.</li>
</ul>


<p>Looks like I learned a lot, actually I can do better, time speeding is not in good effect.</p>

<h3>Health</h3>

<ul>
<li>Gain some muscle.</li>
<li>Stalled at the second half of the year.</li>
<li>Join a gym, hope not waste my money.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Events</h3>

<ul>
<li>Visit lots of place in Shangrao as an event organizor.</li>
<li>Drive around all the districts in Shangrao downtown.</li>
<li>Go to Shanghai in the March for join ruby monthly meeting, and 上海暴走团 event.</li>
<li>Go to Shanghai in the August for join ruby monthly meeting, and 上海暴走团 event.</li>
<li>Go to Beijing in the October for join ruby yearly meeting, visit lots of place in Beijing.</li>
</ul>


<p>It is good to join the events out of my city, after eveluated.</p>

<h3>Summary</h3>

<p>I have had good days in 2014, mostly. Got some archivement both in career and life.
It is unexpected at the beginning of 2014, but is reasonable because of the previous effort.
In 2014, I was not studing/working/thinking hard enough, may have bad result in the future if I&rsquo;m doing the same way.
Got more resposibility now, hard to keep on with the same speed, and left back from others already.
2015 is the last year before I&rsquo;m 30, hope I can do better.</p>

<h2>Plan for the next year</h2>

<p>In the long run, I hope I can be a international level programmer, have a good life, got enough money to speed even when I&rsquo;m not working. For archive that, I need got some progress this year about life, work, and cash flow. What I want to be done:</p>

<ul>
<li>Keep learning: finish reading rails source code, keep learning things about network, linux, frontend.</li>
<li>Find a tech direction, and dig deeper.</li>
<li>Prepare the wedding.</li>
<li>Read more books.</li>
<li>Improving English, both oral and writing.</li>
<li>Keeping healthy and fit.</li>
<li>Connect with the local community.</li>
<li>Keeping connection with great people online.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[old is better]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.linjunhalida.com/blog/english-old-is-better/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-27T22:28:42+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.linjunhalida.com/blog/english-old-is-better</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We programmers face a pitfall: there are always new things to learn. like nodejs, swift, programming languages, development tools,
machine learning, statistics, UI design, etc&hellip;</p>

<p>Time is scare, life can be wasted by learn new things. The more you spend on learning, the more time you are wasting.</p>

<p>New knowledge may has those porperties:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>Unstable</code>: With limited man power and usecase, you may face lots of unneccessary challenges.</li>
<li><code>Limited Domain</code>: Those knowledge are limited under some special case, learned but never used.</li>
<li><code>Homogenization</code>: Another dynamic typing, functional, script programming language.</li>
<li><code>Too much for an human Brain</code>: A dev team have frontend, backend, designer is for good reason. those knowledge are not fit for one man&rsquo;s brain.</li>
</ul>


<p>Because of those properties, I recommand learn old things other then new one:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>Tested by time</code>: Like C, shell, even English, those are the things you will eventually use.</li>
<li><code>Fundamantal</code>: tcp/ip protocol, Operation System, Database, Baisc Algorithm, maybe you are not using them everyday, that will bring great value when time comes.</li>
<li><code>The thing you are using</code>: Level up is better than learn a new skill.</li>
</ul>


<p>Also, there are cases I think we can learn new things:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>Take Small Step</code>: You can take an overview, but deside before further learning.</li>
<li><code>Expend current domain</code>: You can learn things which is supplement for your current knowledge domain, like you are a web developer, learn async web frameworks.</li>
<li><code>Better replacement of current ones</code>: If you are PHP programmer, try to learn Rails.</li>
<li><code>Next step abour your career</code>: If you want to be an data scientist, you need learn lots about statistic.</li>
</ul>


<p>Most of the time, investment on an old knowledge is better then the new one. An jack-of-all-trades programmer is cheaper than a domain expert.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[how to mount disk to linux operation system]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.linjunhalida.com/blog/english-linux-disk-format/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-16T17:33:42+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.linjunhalida.com/blog/english-linux-disk-format</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://product-images.www8-hp.com/digmedialib/prodimg/lowres/c03690405.png" alt="image" /></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve bought a <a href="http://www8.hp.com/cn/zh/products/disk-backup/product-detail.html?oid=6280791">NAS</a> as home server recently, so I&rsquo;ve considered how to mount disk on it by using linux operating system.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve got SSD and HDD, SSD is faster, but is more expensive, and write time limit. So SSD should mount at <code>/</code>, OS will run faster. Writing frequently location like <code>/home</code>, <code>/var</code> should mount on HDD, Temporary location <code>/tmp</code> should mount to file system <code>tmpfs</code>.</p>

<p>About choosing file system. SSD can use <code>ext4</code> with <a href="http://superuser.com/questions/228657/which-linux-filesystem-works-best-with-ssd">some adjustment</a> to reduce write, HDD can use <code>ext4</code> for ordinary use, if used for file sharing and service, <a href="http://doc.freenas.org/9.3/freenas_intro.html#zfs-primer">ZFS</a> is a good fit: Compressed storage, higher ID throughput.</p>

<p>If you want setup NAS disk array, RAID0 is the simplest solution, multiple disks handle IO in the same time. If you have to store some important data, use RAID2: dual disk write the same data. But RAID1 spend too much disk space, software RAID5 can balance it well enough. If you know nothing about RAID, you can watch <a href="http://www.acnc.com/raid">this demo</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[personal data backup method]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.linjunhalida.com/blog/english-backup-method/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-13T18:35:40+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.linjunhalida.com/blog/english-backup-method</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m thinking about how to backup personal data, we can divide them into groups which according to their importance, file size, and privacy.</p>

<ul>
<li>Important, Big size, Sensitive: Computer full disk data.</li>
<li>Important, Small size, Sensitive: key information, like daily.</li>
<li>Unimportant, Middle size, Sensitive: photos.</li>
<li>Unimportant, Big size, insensitive: film, comics.</li>
</ul>


<p>We can use different methods to backup them, vary in price, space, security, and usability:</p>

<ul>
<li>Encrypted online backup service: high price, small space, secure, hard to use.</li>
<li>Online backup service: fair price, small space, insecure, easy to use.</li>
<li>NAS/Portable disk drive: low price, big space, secure, hard to use.</li>
</ul>


<p>So, this is the method I&rsquo;m using now:</p>

<ul>
<li>Use timemachine to backup computer into portable disk drive.</li>
<li>Use <a href="https://lastpass.com/">lastpass</a> to keep website and server password.</li>
<li>Use dropbox to save and sync notes, photos, and documents, I extended it to 20G.</li>
<li>Use portable disk drive to backup film, music and comics.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[how to use gem]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.linjunhalida.com/blog/english-gem/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-07T09:48:29+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.linjunhalida.com/blog/english-gem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m a rails developer, as a benefit of rails developer, I&rsquo;ve got lots of <a href="http://rubygems.org/">Gems</a>.
Gem is flaring, but handle without enough care, it may cut your finger bleeding.
As a jeweler, I can share some knowledge about it.</p>

<h2>Search</h2>

<p>First thing to do is search the gem. search google by describe it, like <code>rails tagging</code>,
or you can browse the list at <a href="https://www.ruby-toolbox.com/">ruby toolbox</a>.</p>

<h2>Pick</h2>

<p>You should pick the right gem with enough quality. there are lots of unqualified, unmaintained shitty gems there,
you don&rsquo;t want to touch them. take a look at the following count on its github project page, and update activity.</p>

<p>You should think first before import it into your project, how its complexity level? is is stable enough? can it be extended?
Other than use the whole gem, you can copy one of it&rsquo;s files into your project to reduce the overhead.
Some gem may change rails module, handle them with caution.</p>

<h2>Use</h2>

<p>Gem version need to be fixed, accidentially upgrading it may cause unexpected bug.</p>

<p>You must know what you have done, read gem documents, wiki, know how to use it.
I prefer figure out how gem works by read the source code, so if something goes wrong, you know how to deal with it.</p>

<p>When something bad happens, check the gem project issue page,
or you can debug it yourself by add log to the gem source code.</p>

<p>You need write document about what you have learned, history repeats itself, you don&rsquo;t want to solve the same issue more than once, like <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/9050419/cant-install-rmagick-2-13-1-cant-find-magickwand-h">install issue of rmagick</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
